<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[how to be]]></title>
  <link href="http://adrichman.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://adrichman.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-05T19:15:14-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://adrichman.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Adam D Richman]]></name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[taco count]]></title>
    <link href="http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2014/01/05/taco-count/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-05T18:46:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2014/01/05/taco-count</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>after &lt;24hrs: 4</p>

<p>also, cracked a rib, I&rsquo;m pretty sure</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[planes, trains and automobiles]]></title>
    <link href="http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2014/01/04/planes/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-04T16:51:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2014/01/04/planes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Getting this journey off on the right foot&hellip;
the right foot being the one that slipped on the stairs at 5am and dealt my lower back and kidneys a blow to remember.</p>

<p>This after a night spent trying to find a way out of NYC in time to arrive in SFO monday a.m. <a href="http://www.delta.com">Delta</a> cancelled my flight at 10pm, but the website crashed and I couldn&rsquo;t get a hold of an agent until 9 hours later. By that time I&rsquo;d taken things into my own hands. Booked the only ticket out of Baltimore that would connect me to the bay area (a first class seat for 80,000 miles fuuuucck), booked a ticket on Amtrak out of Manhattan to get me to BWI in time to catch that flight, and put the rest into fate&rsquo;s hands.</p>

<p>Happy to have discovered the <a href="http://flightaware.com/miserymap/">Misery Map</a>, and with one more segment left on this trip (writing from layover in DTW), this might actually all end fairly well.</p>

<p>Except for the internal bleeding.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[code review]]></title>
    <link href="http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2014/01/03/code-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-03T13:05:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2014/01/03/code-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the midst of the emotional gauntlet of the recent past, I think I actually managed to learn some stuff. I am reminiscing about my first day at <a href="http://www.ad60.com">AD60</a> in October. It took almost the entire day to get set up with 4 Windows IE VirtualBoxes because our client needed support for IE8, ruby, git, and get rails and mysql playing nicely on the mac mini. I remember my friend and boss Dan sitting me down, giving me a list of everything I need to setup my dev environment, then getting access to the repo on <a href="http://www.github.com/adrichman">github</a> and forking it in order to get cracking at some <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira">JIRA tickets</a>. Dan assigned me a ticket and came over to explain in further detail what needed to be done. I jumped right in to the code and&hellip; holy shit I did not know what the fuck I was looking at. My rails tutorials did not prepare me for so many models, controllers and views. I have a terrible memory of details (and generalities), so, from referencing github I am reminded that my first contribution to the code was to write a custom validation. It felt great when I finished it, and it felt less great 2 months later when I learned I had screwed it up and was calculating the cumulative file size of every instance of this particular model in the database, as opposed to the instances that belonged to the user who is currently logged in (duh). But really, writing a statement that actually didn&rsquo;t piss off rails felt like enough of an achievment at the time.</p>

<p>I only worked that job for a couple months before I had to leave and get ready to go to SF, but I must say, I reflected during my last week in the office and marvelled at how familiar I had become with the product, all of the corresponding models and controllers (although I don&rsquo;t think I ever got used to HAML). The education they provided me so graciously was invaluable at codifying my understanding of OOP and the rails framework. I even grew to not hate ruby, despite it&rsquo;s loosy goosy joke of a syntax. Are those arguments? I couldn&rsquo;t tell. They&rsquo;re just floating there without any parenthetical notation.</p>

<p>Oh and then there was the entire week (it seemed) of trying to rename files hosted on S3. Don&rsquo;t bother trying. Seriously. Just rename it on the client side and move the fuck on with your life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[tightroping]]></title>
    <link href="http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2014/01/03/tightroping/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-03T11:56:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2014/01/03/tightroping</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Pack it up, Pack it in. Let me begin&hellip;</h2>

<hr />

<p>Damn. This last week or so of my life has caught me feeling exceptionally fragile.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>
I have been struggling to manage responsibilities I took on as they all culminate in the same moment. While I agressively <a href="http://BrooklynStudioSale.com">marketed the studio</a> with Google Adwords, Facebook Ads and tons of posts and messages from <a href="http://twitter/Adam_D_Richman">my twitter</a> and <a href="http://www.facebook.com/adam.d.richman">facebook account</a>, things were coming together much slower than I hoped, while still creating a sense of light at the end of the tunnel. This felt so true that I pushed my travel back a few days to SF for <a href="http://www.hackreactor.com">Hack Reactor</a> because I really thought I was close to making a deal. Now I&rsquo;m not sure what the outcome will be, and any hope of it being resolved before I leave town is extinguished. And while I wanted a few days in SF to settle in before immersing into the insane program schedule, now I&rsquo;m left with about 36 hours before the going head-first into the fire.</p>

<p>But, it&rsquo;s reminding me of some important facts of life that are easy to say and not easy to experience. For that, I am grateful. Many things are never in our control, so I prefer not to pin my happiness on my hopes. It&rsquo;s a bonus when they come true, but I can&rsquo;t let their fruition be my necessity.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s terribly overwhelming to pack up the studio in the mindset of, possibly, not returning to it. There is a memory tucked into every nook. It has been a home for my passion and work, a home for my family and most recently a home for my new beginning. It&rsquo;s been a struggle to fully begin, however, among all these relics and ghosts. Packing up just unearths them and it feels all-the-more real, heavy, and sad.</p>

<p>The upside to my state of mind is that I can&rsquo;t wait for what&rsquo;s waiting for me, whatever it may be. It feels empowering to be facing such a big change with zero trepidation. I was sad to leave my intern post at <a href="http://www.ad60.com">AD60</a> and that makes me all-the-more stoked to become a &lsquo;real&rsquo; coder. I haven&rsquo;t been in a &lsquo;formal&rsquo; learning environment since 2001, so that&rsquo;s going to be quite a change of pace. I feel endlessly fortunate to have such an opportunity made available to me, and even more fortunate to have the ability to follow it down.</p>

<p>And the lingering question on my mind&hellip; Is this my last day living in New York City?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hello, world]]></title>
    <link href="http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2013/11/11/hello_world/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-11T22:58:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2013/11/11/hello_world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a minute since I addressed my friends at large, which is probably a good thing, because what friend enjoys hearing about a friend via broadcast? Since announcing that my studio <a href="http://thebucketnyc.com">The Bucket NYC</a> is on the market to be leased or bought, I&rsquo;ve received a lot of friendly inquiries in the spirit of WTF?! Some moments call for finding a less exhaustive approach to catching up, so hopefully this can fill in some blanks and form an overly-long answer to that question.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sharing this in order to mark this moment and air out a little of what I&rsquo;ve kept hidden away. This is not intended to sound pitiful or important. It&rsquo;s just something about me, for anyone who cares about reading it.
So here&rsquo;s what&rsquo;s up.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>2013 has been pivotal</h2>

<hr />

<p>To start with, I began the year newly separated from my wife, and eventually divorced.
Not one week of this year felt the same as any other. My joy was as fleeting as my sadness. My confidence was as comforting as it was fragile. I fought to sort my inner voice from my always-judging super-ego.
I began work to achieve balance in each day:
I practiced <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Artists-Way-Julia-Cameron/dp/1585421464">the artist’s way</a> and re-sparked my creativity.
I started <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blood_type_diet">eating for my blood type</a>, running regularly and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0018SLEF8">practicing yoga</a>.
I leaned hard on my friends, and I felt them lean back.
I was struck with an idea for a mobile app by which I became very inspired.
This led to me getting serious about learning to build the first version of the app.
I took courses online ( <a href="http://startup.stanford.edu/,">http://startup.stanford.edu/,</a> <a href="http://codeschool.com">http://codeschool.com</a> ) and became all the more driven and intrigued.
I submitted extensive applications to a few competitive, immersive coding programs.
I began interning for a digital agency here in brooklyn (<a href="http://www.ad60.com">AD:60</a>).
After multiple technical interviews, I was offered a spot at <a href="http://hackreactor.com">Hack Reactor</a> in San Fransisco, and I accepted.
I will begin there in the first week of 2014, and will, hopefully, come up for air 12 weeks later as a much better programmer.</p>

<h2>Learning to fly</h2>

<hr />

<p>Being a musician has long felt to be a defining quality for me, and moreso as being a career musician, rather than a musician by love and talent. I don&rsquo;t remember a time when I felt like my identity as a musician didn&rsquo;t walk into a room one step ahead of me.</p>

<p>I recall that for a long time, my canned, and candid, response to compliments regarding my gift &ndash; the luck of being &ldquo;talented&rdquo; &ndash; was always the same. &ldquo;The gift,&rdquo; I&rsquo;d explain with genuine humility, &ldquo;is that I have the fire to go hack at this every day.&rdquo; I never took for granted that I was driven to move forward.</p>

<p>In the time since the beginning of 2011 or so, I took notice when that feeling left. I waited it out for a long time, without the ability to even indicate to myself what would make me happy. I turned my whole life upside down, pining for something that could make me happy again. And even though I know that happiness is wanting what you have, I knew I wasn&rsquo;t going to be able to spin this around without some very big changes.</p>

<p>In these previous years, I was overwhelmed with fear. Of not living up to my own ideals, of interrupting the romantic narrative I had for my life&rsquo;s story, of disappointing my family and friends, of being an inadequate partner, of being a failure and a hack. All of this is classically symptomatic of depression, but I mistook it for my universal truth for a very long time. I sought help, and I managed to break out of the negative feedback loop with the assistance of a professional and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bupropion">Wellbutrin XL</a>.</p>

<p>Damnit if it doesn&rsquo;t feel good to be on the other side of that. I don&rsquo;t imagine that anything could make me feel that affraid and paralyzed in my own life ever again. Once I confronted my greatest fears and resolved to live for myself despite the consequences of external judgement &ndash; fear was no more.</p>

<p>I am on a journey, for now, to discover and separate the man from the musician. Not to cut music out from my life &ndash; it will always be as crucial to me as oxygen &ndash; but to come out from under it and walk with another purpose. I actually feel more in touch with the essence of my affinity for music and audio than I have in many, many years. In my musical career, I never stuck to one sound, genre or aesthetic. I am acutely aware of how much that restlessness is baked into my bones. I am at peace knowing that my life may be a series of curious non-sequitors. But I am also very single-mindedly focussed right now on this next phase; focused on learning, meeting monumental challenges, and creating in a new medium. I&rsquo;m prepared. There&rsquo;s never been a better time than right now.</p>

<h2>tl;dr</h2>

<hr />

<p>I&rsquo;m learning to be a coder. I&rsquo;m <a href="http://hackreactor.com">studying in San Fransisco</a> from Jan &lsquo;14 &ndash; Apr &#8216;14. Single and ready to mingle with javaScript.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[and I should mention...]]></title>
    <link href="http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2013/10/14/mention/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-14T21:06:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2013/10/14/mention</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a little excited to let time turn this blog into some kind of measuring stick for my progress in this new realm (for me). But it needs some catch-up from the last six+ months that started me down this path. I am going to get on that by the end of the week.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[winning the battle but...]]></title>
    <link href="http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2013/10/14/winning_the_battle/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-14T20:51:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://adrichman.github.io/blog/2013/10/14/winning_the_battle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>battled for an embarrasingly long time with this problem for coderbyte:</h2>

<blockquote><p>Using the JavaScript language, have the function PermutationStep(num) take the num parameter
being passed and return the next number greater than num using the same digits. For example:
if num is 123 return 132, if it&rsquo;s 12453 return 12534. If a number has no greater permutations,
return -1 (ie. 999).</p>

<p>Input = 11121 Output = 11211
Input = 41352 Output = 41523</p></blockquote>

<p>My original solution didn&rsquo;t take too terribly long, and it was able to pass all my test cases, but then coderbyte&rsquo;s response informed me that it failed for a really exhaustive case such as 897654321. I was exceeding my stack limit on that case, so I rethought ways to keep the permutations to the minimum. Really happy I that I pulled through it because the result also runs much faster.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/adrichman/coderbyte/blob/master/PermutationStep.not_exhaustive.js">Github::PermutationStep.not_exhaustive.js</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
